# Ramesh Ojha

Having 4 years of experience in programming (mostly in frontend), and I am looking for a good opportunity where I can enhance my core skills. I also have an engineering degree and have good knowledge of computer science and information technologies. Currently pursuing master's course from online distance education.

# **Work Experience**

# Senior Software Engineer, Coforge Limited

Dec 2023 - Present

- Worked on complicated screens development with approximately 10-15 API calls on single page.
- Did R&D, POC and implementation of Dark Mode from scratch.
- Followed test driven development approach for repo migration.
- Wrote unit test cases for old legacy project where increased code coverage from 35% to approximately 80%.
- Worked on technologies like NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Axios, MUI, Storybook, Jest (RTL), HTML, SCSS, GIT and AWS.

# Solution Engineer, Degode

Jun 2021 - Dec 2023

- Did R&D, POC and implementation of whitelabeling in the legacy project based on automated chat-support application.
- Debugged production level bugs and resolved it in quick time.
- Created atomic and molecular components for UI in ReactJS.
- Have implemented servers and connected it to database.
- Worked on TypeScript, NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, ExpressJS, MongoDB, GrapghQL, Socket.io, GIT, Jenkins and AWS.

# Project Intern, Sudhya Developer Core

Dec 2020 - March 2021

- Got exposure to full stack web app development (e-commerce application)
- Participated in creating CRUD operation code on server.
- · Did code reading and code cleanup.
- Technology used ReactJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, TypeORM, NodeJS.

## **Educational Background**

# Master of Computer Application (MCA) (Pursuing Currently)

Indra Gandhi National Open University

Jan 2023 - Present

· Learning DSA, ML, AI, Python and System Design.

## **Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering**

Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam Technical University Aug 2013 - Jul 2018

• Got exposure to C, C++, HTML and CSS.

#### Contact

Noida Sector 59 +91-9540205885 +91-9205018942 rameshojha3108@gmail.com www.rameshojha.com Leetcode - rameshojha3131 freecodecamp.org/rameshojha github.com/RameshOj

## **Skills**

#### **Frontend Skills**

- · NextJS, ReactJS, Redux
- HTML, CSS, SCSS
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- JQery, MUI

## **Backend Skills**

- ExpressJS
- MongoDB, TypeORM
- Python

#### **Additional Skills**

- · Jenkins, Vercel, ArgoCD
- · Jest, RTL, Enzyme
- · Python, Docker
- Socket.io, Open Al API's
- AWS S3, EC2, Elastic Beanstalk

## **Certification/Short Courses**

- Responsive Web Designing
- Javascript Algorithm & Data Structure
- Frontend Development Libraries
- NextJs
- Advanced React & Storybook

## **Additional Information**

- Managing 2-3 Junior Developers in my current project.
- Participate in extra curricular activites and campus sports competition.